My name is Peppa
And this is my little brother George
This is Mummy Pig
This is Daddy Pig
And I'm Peppa
[Mysteries]
Peppa and her family
are watching their favourite TV show
"Potato Detective"
I am Potato Detective
I'm a world-famous detective
Please help me, Mr Detective
I can't find my flower anywhere
Well, the flower you're looking for is right on your head
Oh, thank you, Mr Detective
That's easy, I could've done that
I'm sure you could
Daddy, when I grow up
I want to be a very famous detective
George wants to be a detective too!
If you want to be detectives
you each need a hat
Detectives always wear hats, you know
Now you both look like real detectives
We also need that funny thing
that makes everything look bigger
That's a magnifying glass
I think there's one in the kitchen drawer
Here it is
A real magnifying glass
Wow, how does it work?
You hold it in front of something
and that thing looks bigger
The magnifying glass made the goldfish look bigger
Can I try?
Wow!
The magnifying glass made George's eye look huge
Now, what you two detectives need
is a mystery to solve
Daddy, what's a... cookie case?
It's a mystery, not a cookie
This is what detectives are best at solving
Like finding things that are lost
I know!
We can find George's dinosaur
He's always losing it
Dinosaur!
Mr Dinosaur isn't lost
Oh, why don't we find your glasses, Daddy
You're always saying you can't find them
They're not lost today!
My glasses are right here
Oh no, that's no good
So there's no cookie mystery for me to solve?
You want me to make up some mysteries for you to solve?
Yes please
Daddy Pig is going to make up some mysteries
Now, what's on the table?
There's a little fish, a teddy bear
a jack-in-the-box, and Mr Dinosaur too
That's right
Now watch closely
Try to remember them
There's a fish, a teddy bear
a jack-in-the-box clown, and Mr. Dinosaur
Have you remembered them all?
Got them all
Good
You two wait outside for a bit
I'll call you when I'm ready
That sounds like Daddy going up the stairs
Now he should be coming back down
All done, you can come back in now
Something's gone missing from the table
Do you know what it is?
There's Mr. Dinosaur
the fish, the jack-in-the-box clown
So who's missing?
Um... the teddy bear
That's exactly right, the teddy bear is missing
Peppa, George, you're so clever!
This is easy for us
Because we're famous detectives
But this mystery is only half solved
Where did the teddy bear go?
Oh, I don't know
What are those little bits on the floor?
Those are cake crumbs
With a magnifying glass
it's easy to see those are cake crumbs
I wonder if the teddy bear was eating cake earlier?
The cake crumbs go this way
The teddy bear must have eaten a lot of cake
The cake crumbs lead all the way to Peppa and George's room
Oh, the crumbs lead here
How do we find the teddy bear?
Ask me some questions
But I'll only answer 'yes' or 'no'
Okay then
Is the teddy bear in this room?
Yes
Is the teddy bear on George's bed?
No
Is the teddy bear somewhere high up?
Yes
The teddy bear is on my bed
-Yay!
Mystery solved!
Do you want to be a detective when you grow up, Peppa?
Actually, being a detective isn't easy at all, it's really hard
Next time, I'd rather be the one who makes up the mysteries
Just like you, Daddy